♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world,
we shall hold the balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Be brave enough to split
the primal chaos wide open♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
Who is it?
Father.
It is me.
You grow ever less mannered.
Why not wait to be announced?
Father.
I have words for you.
You have grown up,
and you've grown bolder as well.
As a child, I saw you give
the Dragon Gate Token to Jia.
All the Dragon Palace praised him.
And I could only use a fake token
to play childish games with the maids.
I must have disappointed you.
Did you come here
to say this to me?
Yes.
No.
Father,
I want...
I want to ask you for an order
to stop Jia.
How insolent.
Brat.
What do you know of war and statecraft?
And you dare lecture me?
But do you know Jia is now
hunting down Qi refiners?
Or...
Do you pretend
not to know?
Jia has his own judgment.
He won't.
He's still stuck in the past,
when the Dragon Clan ruled the world.
But human powerhouses emerge endlessly,
while we dragons make no changes,
still living in the past.
It's time
for us to wake up.
Yi.
Good.
It looks like you've truly grown up.
But since every word you say is right,
why don't you tell your brother?
I will.
[Episode 10]
Finally, you're out alone.
Who are you?
You don't need to know.
You only need to know
that I'm here to kill you.
To flee the Dragon Palace,
you must open the Water Dragon Spout.
In the Dragon Palace,
those who can open the Spout
are only the Dragon King
and his two sons.
The First Prince won't open it.
The Dragon King won't intervene.
So,
Ascendance Sect's only hope of rescue
is Ao Yi.
You want me to kill Ao Yi?
For the First Prince to rule East Sea,
the Second Prince has to go eventually.
Why not use this chance
to frame the Human Clan?
Okay.
Remember what you promised:
Once I've done this for you,
you'll let me return to Ascendance Sect.
Not only that.
I'll help you spread the rumors
that the dragons' invitation
is a conspiracy.
Ascendance Sect disciples
were decimated.
Only you fought free.
At that time,
you'll be a hero to the Human Clan.
Perfect.
I can also conveniently eliminate
those defiant sect disciples.
After you die,
the First Prince can be at ease
as the Crown Prince.
Nonsense.
My brother and I share a deep bond.
How could he send someone to kill me?
I've heard
of the Dragon Transformation Art.
Since you are a dragon prince,
why not fight in dragon form?
You asked for this.
Transform into a dragon.
Just as the rumors said.
Though you bear the Dragon's Prophecy,
you cannot transform at all.
A dragon heir who cannot transform
is not worth living.
Here I come!
Shoot!
I see.
Sir,
it's you.
Who are you?
State your name!
I never bother with formalities.
If I told you just because you asked...
Sure, we can tell you.
This is Changgeng.
You're Changgeng?
I am Changgeng?
There's no need to hide it.
The day we parted,
you pointed your finger skyward,
facing the distant west.
As they say, Qiming in the east;
Changgeng in the west.
That is your name, Changgeng.
You're indeed clever.
This humble one is called Changgeng.
I never change my name.
What? Are you not convinced?
Well said.
Young man, do you remember my words?
Of course.
I'll go find my brother
to open the Water Dragon Spout.
That won't be necessary.
[Token]
The Dragon Gate Token?
What are you laughing at?
You go ahead.
I'll stay here and play with him.
Okay.
I'm an Aureate Immortal.
You're no match for me.
What demon are you?
Where's your martial honor?
Face me head-on if you dare.
Stop these lowly tricks.
They're surprisingly powerful.
No, no.
I need a rest.
Open the Dragon Gate now,
and let us out!
Dream on.
The Dragon Gate Token
is with His Highness.
No one's opening it.
I'll kill you!
[Token]
The Dragon Gate Token is here.
Your Highness.
Everyone,
I'll use the Token to open
the Water Dragon Spout.
Leave now.
Jia.
Do you know what you're doing?
I...
Get back there!
Trying to run?
The one who killed Yecha
has been executed at the Eye of the Sea.
Senior Changshou.
You may not be the killers,
but you are all his accomplices.
Spare none.
Yes.
I will avenge Senior Changshou.
I'm an Aureate Immortal.
How could I lose
to a sneaking coward like you?
Come out! Let's fight again.
Kuai Si?
You dare call me a sneaking coward?
I wasn't talking about you.
Kill this one first.
Don't attack!
I am not your enemy.
I'm not your match.
Elder Kuai Si.
You said you came for your disciples,
so I sent you on your way.
You're welcome.
Do I need to tell everyone
what happened?
I was held up
by Dragon Palace troops.
Thanks to this cultivator's help,
I could come and join you all.
Thank you, Changgeng.
Don't mention it.
Changgeng?
I've never heard of him.
Just another human scoundrel.
The Human Clan has no good folk.
Kill them.
The Fairy is so thoughtful.
Yunxiao, you needed me?
With your cultivation, rascal,
I'm afraid you can't comprehend
the wonder of Resonance.
You saw through me that easily?
You needn't speak to me.
As you can see,
this is a projection formed
by a trace of my Resonance.
So, it's a recording.
You coaxed me away;
the one who lured me here
will surely not let you off.
So, I left a tenth of my power
in the Resonance
to help you survive this calamity.
After all,
this matter began because of me.
I suppose you'll ask me
why I would help you.
Because you're a useful pawn.
I may need you later.
So, you don't have to die just yet.
You're quite honest.
But if you don't believe me...
Of course, I believe you.
For all these years,
I've hidden behind a cold facade,
pretending to be
heartless and unfeeling.
But I never expected you
to see right through me.
Well.
Not entirely...
Remember:
The Resonance power will run out.
Cherish it.
♪Once a drifting weed, I loved to roam♪
♪Now, a levee holds back the storm♪
Primordial Vessel.
Open!
I...
My hammer!
Yunxiao is truly thoughtful.
Primordial Vessel?
He can do this too.
Move!
♪Plain and unremarkable♪
♪From the start, plan for storms♪
♪Seek refuge, survive, hide my skill♪
♪If smooth, seek peace♪
♪If tough, stay still;
who fates good and evil♪
♪After hardship, sweetness comes;
fear nothing♪
Your Highness, be careful!
♪Mad ones, why ruin your foundation♪
♪The evil knows no shame♪
♪Immortal trials burn cowardice away♪
♪The howling wind calls to me♪
♪Gouging eyes to light the night
and ferry souls♪
♪My soul is standing like a mountain♪
Stay away from him!
Your brother has gone mad now.
All hope of the Human Clan rests on you.
What should I do?
The Dragon Gate Token.
But
the Token is already...
It's all right.
The Dragon King's son
can command the Water Dragon Spout.
I...
Can I?
You can.
Look at me.
The future you.
Ao Yi.
Remember?
Don't you want to become
who you truly wish to be
and transform into a dragon?
Trust me. You can do it.
Can I?
Yes.
Are you two close?
Why all this pointless chatter?
Shut up.
Sect disciples, prepare to retreat.
Who are you?
Why are you leading my brother astray?
He has grown up now.
He has the right to choose his own path.
If you have the guts, come at me.
Why pick on a minor dragon?
He's still far from growing up.
Far from growing up.
The outcome is decided.
The First Prince wins.
Yi,
you still haven't grown up.
It seems you're still a little dragon.
The Second Prince is still young.
He's no match for the First Prince.
Ao Yi.
Pah!
Stop with that nonsense.
You don't get to decide.
In my eyes,
the Second Prince is resolute.
He's a dragon with great aspirations,
far better than a big dragon like you.
Don't use your authority as his brother
to stunt his growth.
That's rubbish...
Isn't that so?
Silence implies agreement.
See? Your brother agrees.
What a spectacular Water Dragon Spout!
Grander than the Spout
I created back then!
Your Majesty, you're wise.
You're wise indeed!
Sect members, evacuate!
Run!
Okay.
Let's go!
Let's go.
Changgeng,
you're a human, right?
You've got a sharp eye.
Will we see each other again?
If you never forget your true heart,
we will meet again.
Goodbye.
Wretched beast!
♪I don't ask, too lazy to fight♪
♪I dare to live my own way♪
♪In the Primordial World♪
♪Who sings and drinks free♪
♪The stars smile at fireflies♪
♪Roaming the city with reckless courage♪
♪Just watching swordplay while drunk♪
♪And in dreams, I reign supreme♪
♪Who can ever♪
♪Predict the clock of time♪
♪Learn the watches of the night♪
What have you done?
My Dragon Gate Token!
Jia, you've caused a great calamity!
Henceforth,
all your authority is revoked;
your title as the army commander
is stripped for three years.
Father.
Father, this...
♪Karma never falls empty♪
Senior...
Where are you now?
Senior.
What's wrong with your senior?
He was killed by the Crown Prince.
Senior.
You're...
Shh.
Senior, what are you...
This...
Oh, it's you.
But this time,
wasn't it a little too dangerous?
What if the Second Prince
failed to open the Water Dragon Spout?
Then we'd...
You don't even trust me?
Honestly.
Of course, I trust you.
Ao Yi is just Plan A.
Even if he failed,
I still had
Plan B, Plan C, and Plan D.
Senior, you surely played it safe.
Ling'e.
Changshou!
Senior Changshou!
Changshou.
Senior, are you alright?
Senior.
Sorry, sorry.
Glad you're back.
Just having you back is enough.
He needs to rest.
So,
please don't come by unless it's urgent.
Turtle,
regarding what Yi did today,
what do you think?
Utterly preposterous.
Acting purely on a whim.
What he did really surprised me.
Good.
Indeed, indeed. He did well.
Yeah.
I also believe that, given time,
the Second Prince
will surely ease the burdens
of you and the First Prince.
Enough.
Don't waste time guessing my will.
Just speak plainly.
Jia has been rash lately.
Have we crossed someone we shouldn't?
I only know
that there have been minor clashes
between the Human and Dragon Clans,
and it was all led by the Crown Prince.
It has nothing to do with you.
You are our only Empyreal Vajra.
No, the only Empyreal Aureate Immortal,
keeping to the shadows,
and never taking a side.
You old turtle,
your flattery keeps getting better.
Well said.
Whew, that was close.
A stray note
broke my whole tune.
I just took a nap,
and you actually
botched such a big plan.
I truly admire you.
My identity has not been revealed.
Yunxiao
is still one of our pieces.
How am I exposed?
How was it botched?
This step
is the only way forward.
What do you think,
cultivator?
The South Sea is my territory.
Be it Fairy Yunxiao or Changgeng,
once they come,
they will all be my playthings.
What arrogance.
Is that really arrogance?
In a few days,
all will be clear.
What scheme have you set now?
Shh.
Listen.
Listen to what?
A new hero is born.
Changgeng
should be even more fun
than Yunxiao.
Aunt.
Senior Changshou nearly lost his life.
He must have gained new insight.
Better not disturb him.
Let's go.
In that case,
Fairy Yunxiao's plot
for the Sea-Calming Pillar is clear.
I also found
someone else behind Fairy Yunxiao.
The motive is unclear,
and the identity is suspicious.
You should pay attention to that.
If you have questions,
feel free to ask.
Li Changshou,
you met Fairy Yunxiao that day.
Did you see a sword on her?
A sword?
Fairy Yunxiao has the Primordial Vessel
and countless magic instruments.
Which sword are you referring to?
Indeed.
Since Fairy Yunxiao
didn't steal the Pillar,
it means
the sword is not with her.
What a relief!
If the Pillar were taken,
it'd be a world-shattering calamity.
Exactly, exactly.
In just a few days,
this young man brought you
such vital info.
Also, he protected the East Sea
and prevented the Pillar's theft.
What talent.
Why not bring him
into the Celestial Court?
Let him serve in my division.
I'll take him.
You're quite eager.
What does that have to do with you?
Li Changshou.
Yes?
You really want to serve
the Celestial Court?
Yeah.
How dare you?
And you want to serve
the Celestial Court?
You just said you stopped Fairy Yunxiao.
Why not bring her here
for judgment?
Well.
How could I manage that?
True.
Of course, you couldn't.
But then again,
you could at least report to me.
Let me ask you.
Where is Fairy Yunxiao?
Where did she go?
Where are the stolen treasures?
How to restore them?
How to punish her?
You can at least answer those questions.
I have to handle that?
Isn't it Celestial Court business?
How dare you!
Eastwood Duke.
You dare shirk responsibility?
No, not at all.
The Celestial Court's duties.
Do you know its duties?
Listen, here are the rules:
Credit goes to high immortals.
Blame falls on minor officials.
Minor officials.
Here are the rules:
If done well,
it's due to wise leadership.
If done poorly, you're incompetent.
Exactly.
The Celestial Court had a grand plan.
After extensive inquiries,
we learned that Fairy Yunxiao
would seize the Sea-Calming Pillar,
so we cast a perfect net,
waiting for that demoness to appear.
And now, look.
She's vanished!
And it's all your fault!
You ruined our scheme!
This...
Me?
Enough!
If you want to atone,
bring Fairy Yunxiao
to the Celestial Court!
Yes. No...
I...
Stop with that mumbling!
Go now!
Changshou!
The Celestial Court feels familiar.
Tian.
At your service.
Answer me:
How long until the Great Tribulation?
Thirty years remain.
Thirty years?
Last time, it was fifty.
Please look at it from a broader view.
As Eastwood Duke said,
if the Sea-Calming Pillar is stolen,
it will bring disaster to all.
Could this be the Great Tribulation
Fate spoke of?
Did things happen sooner
because I let Fairy Yunxiao go?
No, no!
No.
I must bring her back
and make up for it.
I must reach Celestial Court soon.
Senior.
Senior, you're awake.
Come here. Stop!
Junior.
Cover me.
Why is it always me?
Where's Changshou?
Where is he?
Where's Senior Changshou?
He...
He went to sweep his parents' graves.
Sweeping graves?
Sweeping graves...
He's indeed loyal and filial.
He cultivates yet remembers his roots.
That's right.
Wait a moment.
His parents?
His family is long deceased.
He's quite resilient.
This...
Near the sea?
Is he a fisherman?
Surely not a merman, right?
His family
must have endured so much hardship.
Senior,
may you find peace and return safely.
This is absolutely unbearable!
The Second Prince
is still sleeping at high noon.
How enviable, indeed.
He didn't get a wink
of sleep last night,
rambling on till the wee hours.
What was he saying?
He talked of venturing
to the human world
and studying from the Human Clan.
The Second Prince
hardly ever leaves the Dragon Palace.
And he met so many friends all at once.
He might just be overexcited.
Indeed.
He even kept me up,
claiming that humans
are the wisest of all,
and for the Dragon Clan to rise,
we must learn from the human strength.
So, what did you say?
I said, "You're still young."
"His Majesty would never let you out."
At that, Second Prince got angry,
hid under the quilt,
and wouldn't speak to me.
Your Highness.
Is sleeping late
a human strength too?
Your Highness.
Don't sleep with your head
covered like that.
Your Highness!
Where is he?
Did he truly go to train
in the human world?
Forgive me, Father.
For our clan's future, I must leave.
After I finish my studies,
I'll become a ray of light
to lead our clan
back to glory.
What is happening?
I failed?
You can do it, Ao Yi.
You can do it.
I can do it.
As I recall,
you were at just this age
when you set sail to train.
Then, you made
the empire you have today.
This déjà vu
really moved me.
Turtle,
what are you saying?
I don't understand a word of this.
Well, yes.
I said nothing.
I saw nothing.
Don't cry.
Don't cry, don't cry.
There, there.
Yi will come back.
He'll be back very soon.
So, this is the human world?
The scent of my benefactor.
Fairy Yunxiao's Resonance lingers here
and then stops abruptly.
Not a single trace.
Where did she go?
I see.
But that's so far.
No means of transport at all?
[Bear Island, South Sea]
[Xiong Da]
I've lost weight.
[Xiong Er]
This is hardly enough to eat.
Yeah, look how thin they all are.
Including me, my arm...
Even my belly has gotten smaller.
You've worked hard, Da.
Where's our little sister?
Xiong Lingli.
Xiong Lingli!
Here.
[Xiong Lingli]
Come give me a hand.
So big!
Such a big fish!
This must weigh over a thousand jin!
We'll have meat to eat, Da.
We'll have meat to eat.
This is enough for two or three meals.
Lingli, you need to eat more.
You're still growing.
Sure.
Ah, Li Changshou.
Tell me.
Where does your heart truly belong?
[Jiu Jiu]
Not her.
[Youqin Xuanya]
[Lan Ling'e]
Not her.
Then who could it be?
This is baffling me.
Moon Elder.
Who?
Is that you, Changshou?
[Li Changshou]
Changshou?
Changshou...
I found her at last.
Finally.
I've got to see
who your true love really is.
Fairy Yunxiao?
[Yunxiao]
Everything went smoothly.
Mostly.
Go scout.
Something's wrong.
Empyreal Vase.
Big Dipper Sword.
Ghostvein Powder.
Thunderheart Art.
Why did all my trump cards fail?
Where's my magical power?
Guess.
You rascal.
You truly followed my Resonance here.
It was you
who lured me here.
I thought you'd arrive sooner.
It seems I overestimated
your cultivation.
So, you took my power?
What do you think?
Who are you really?
Who told you
to seize the Skyscraping Vine
and storm the Crystal Palace?
And for what reason?
I've never pried, Yunxiao.
And please,
don't press me for answers.
I've read many esoteric books,
yet I've never heard
of any spell
that can seize
one's magical power so entirely.
How did you manage
that?
Answer my question first.
Watch out, Yunxiao!
I thought...
I thought
only I was trapped here.
You've got sharp eyes.
So, you didn't leave
the Resonance on the sea
to lure me here.
You're also trapped.
That's why you can't retrieve it.
So, is this also why
your Resonance
suddenly cut off outside the island?
The spiritual energy here is thin.
The residents are all mortals.
They have no magic power.
But the one who set the trap here
could seal my power.
I originally thought it was you.
Now, it seems I was overthinking.
Containing my power
isn't hard.
But containing your Quasi-Saint power...
I am an innate being
beyond the Three Realms
and the Five Elements.
But my power was also sealed.
That only means that the curse here
is even older than me.
Yunxiao,
someone set a trap here deliberately.
You and I are trapped here.
No.
Only you are trapped here.
When...?
I got here a day before you
and spent all night
filing off these shackles.
You can work on that here tonight.
Now, nobody's trapped here.
How did you...?
I have my way.
Unorthodox way.
Are you here for the sword?
You also know of the Pregenesis Sword?
Of course, I know
of that Pregenesis Sword.
Did the Dragon King tell you?
I didn't expect the Dragon King
to tell you too.
Only he knows that the Pregenesis Sword
undoes the Sea-Calming Pillar's seal.
That sword undoes the seal?
How dare you fish for info from me?
No, no.
I wasn't fishing for info.
I just love listening to you talk.
I'm listening, I'm listening.
You think I can't handle you
without magical power?
Of course, you can.
I know what your deepest fear is.
It's me.
Your eyes show fear.
You fear me, yet you seek me out.
I know you.
You'd never do this.
You'd never invite
such karmic entanglement.
What exactly are you plotting?
The one who sent you
isn't the Dragon King.
It's the Celestial Court.
You're from the Celestial Court.
Yunxiao, someone's coming.
I'm still useful alive.
Why not untie me first?
You'd better be useful.
I'm very useful.
They treated us like prey,
locking us in here.
I have many ways to kill them.
If anyone tries to enter,
the door bolt will stop them.
If it were you,
what would you do?
Ignore the lock,
and push the door open.
If he forces the door open,
the water in the bucket
will come pouring down,
blocking his line of sight.
At the same time, the axe will fall,
leaving him dead or half-crippled.
And that moment
will be our chance.
But what if he turns back first
and peers through a window?
What a coincidence.
I've already spread poison powder
at every window and vent,
waiting for his grand arrival.
♪Let the comings and goings be♪
♪Let the answer be empty♪
I never thought you could set
such a thorough trap
without magic spells.
If you can ambush, why assault head-on?
If poison works, why use spells?
What's with that look?
Unfortunately, all these tricks
may not work on the locals here.
You said they don't know magic spells.
More than that.
They...
Forget it.
You'll see when you meet them.
They're here.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tears fall, this fate's not done♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪